foreign
[Music]
living in the northern part of
Washington state gives me the
opportunity to observe the transition of
the Four Seasons in contrast to milder
environments there is such a distinct
difference between each and every part
of the year
[Music]
since I was a little girl I loved going
out in nature and had the distinct
privilege of being able to call it one
of my teachers I was schooled at home
most of my childhood and I would say
overall my education was defined by
outdoor Expeditions movement endless
reading and writing preserving an
insatiable love of learning into my
adulthood
[Music]
thank you
you've probably heard many different
perspectives on alternative education
both positive and negative I'm not here
to affirm or defend because I know so
many educations traditional
non-traditional and anything in between
can be imperfect and complicated
not everyone has the opportunity to
choose certain forms of Education some
don't have the opportunity to even learn
how to read so this video isn't meant to
say anything except share a story of a
child that grew up mostly Barefoot and
enjoyed an unconventional education and
in some ways childhood having known
nothing to compare it to until she was
older
my homeschool experience enriched my
life and while I would not recommend it
as I don't think it is possible or would
suit everyone sharing stories can be so
beautiful and important for considering
New Perspectives
[Music]
my mother chose to homeschool us partly
because my father was in the military
and we were often moving around for
example between the ages of 13 to
graduation I had the opportunity to go
to about six different high schools
my mother was concerned that this
constant change was difficult for me as
she noticed I was a very sensitive and
often nervous child when I would
experiment with going to Traditional
School I would have a hard time focusing
in a classroom with over 30 students and
couldn't process my lessons Well when
things got noisy and chaotic or when
others were pulling my hair when I was
trying to take a test
[Music]
I was used to using my body throughout
the day to move and exercise often
reading my textbooks while I was walking
around outside it felt strange to me to
sit in a chair for over six hours a day
treating my body as something I wasn't
supposed to use most of the time I'm not
saying this as a criticism of schools
all I know is that I personally struggle
to feel energized when I wasn't able to
move
foreign
[Music]
my mother also decided to homeschool us
because she wanted to keep her native
language alive being native Puerto Rican
her dream was for her children to grow
up being fluent Spanish speakers and I
admit I'm very grateful for that because
it helped me value my Heritage and get
employment opportunities later in life I
became used to taking my books outside
conducting experiments on the dandelions
growing on my sidewalk and visiting a
museum of the opportunity arose to this
day I value connecting and approaching
learning in Dynamic ways and I think
that our public libraries Galleries and
museums can always use more support
foreign
being schooled at home also meant that
my day was much shorter I would do the
same amount of work but there was very
little time spent waiting for other
students or going over Concepts that I
already understood
I had a lot of time left over this was
extremely important for me and that is
why I will always advocate for anyone
struggling with stress or simply hoping
to try something new to embrace mindful
boredom and allow that quiet time
without scheduled activities to help you
understand yourself better in your
passions we so easily fill up our days
to the point that we have no time for
processing our experiences or simply to
be and I think I attribute these values
to being at home a lot growing up taking
charge of my own learning when I had
time off
[Music]
I think it is complete
my schooling was focused on book
learning but we would get kits and
science projects in the mail from an
online program often being able to take
classes online with real teachers I
ended up exceeding expectations
academically and later went on to
University
one aspect of my childhood that is
interesting and a bit strange is that
even though I was involved in clubs and
did social activities all the time I
didn't spend the vast majority of my day
surrounded by peers so I had a lot less
insecurities related to my hobbies and
interests for example I played with
dolls for years after many children
would have stopped playing with them in
exchange for more adult interests
because I simply didn't have a point of
reference so I just liked what I liked
now I definitely see the benefits of
having a thriving peer group but I did
find it interesting that I spent a lot
longer enjoying being a child instead of
trying to act like a young woman which
is what I would see in my friends I
developed and matured at my own pace and
while I don't think this is necessarily
positive or negative it did all work out
in the end as a highly sensitive child
learning to regulate their emotions and
with a vivid imagination I found that
schooling at home helped me take a
growing up at a bit of a slower Pace
that worked for me
my childhood has made me who I am today
and I encourage you no matter what your
age to attempt to ReDiscover the
excitement and interest you had when you
were young maybe back when you were five
years old and building a tower of bricks
at a preschool perhaps you have lost a
little bit of that passion for Learning
and everything just feels like homework
if you give yourself an opportunity to
take an alternative approach to
something that you're trying to learn
you may be surprised by what you
discover I think that when we let go of
judgment so many more opportunities
arise and openness to consider other
stories
[Music]
foreign
I have been working on these embroidery
projects today and it has been snowing
outside which was a bit of a surprise
because it warmed up recently so we've
gotten several more inches of snow and
even though I'm excited for spring this
is really good news for a wonderful
season of wildflowers I have already
been scattering wildflower seeds and
preparing for when it warms up and I'm
so excited I was a little bit reticent
to make a video talking about
homeschooling and alternative schooling
because there are so many strong
opinions out there and I think as well
there's a lot of myths and
misunderstandings depending on people's
experiences so I did want to make it
clear that I was simply sharing my own
experience and the positives of it
because I enjoyed my childhood my
education however there is certainly a
variety of experiences both good and bad
both in traditional and non-traditional
Educational Systems when I first moved
here to the valley I worked at a
Montessori inspired preschool it was
extremely fruitful and it made me really
value all these variety of different
types of education and finding what
works best for the student if those
opportunities are available in the first
place which they not always are in my
personal case
um
homeschooling really benefited me and my
personality both my siblings did it and
enjoyed it but they also thrived in
school in just Traditional School I
however struggled because I found it
very difficult to pay attention in
classes where there were 35 other
students all making noise and often the
classes were quite short they were like
40 minutes and so if I had questions
about something I wanted to learn I was
always running out of time to be able to
ask questions and the sheer amount of
people the noise the distractions just
made it very difficult and overwhelming
for me and I would come home quite
exhausted my mother not only noticed
that when I experienced you know more
traditional schooling I was quite came
home quite exhausted she also noticed
that I was less creative and didn't have
as much interest in hobbies that I once
enjoyed such as music and art because
was I was just so worn out from a day of
just experiences being a more sensitive
child I think I benefited a lot from a
environment that was a lot more quiet
and a lot more focused and I was able to
really spend time really carefully
learning things that I was struggling
with like mathematics I know was
something very difficult for me and I
really needed kind of a one-on-one
support in order to be able to learn
choosing Alternative forms of school can
often be an incredible blessing and a
privilege because that is just not
always possible in many places and on
many family situations my mother as well
is Puerto Rican and in her culture it's
you know very much more normal to have
your children at home all the time and
have multiple Generations in the same
home and so I think the idea of having
her children home all the time instead
of being at school seemed a lot lot less
strange I certainly think that there are
certain personalities and types of
people that struggle to learn and thrive
in environments that are very chaotic
and that was my experience in school and
I'm sure there are many schools that are
able to keep an environment that is not
like that but my experience was that I
just found it very difficult to love
learning I was also in a home that quite
limited technology and there just
weren't wasn't that much technology
available I mean this is the early you
know 2000s and so I think as well I was
very motivated at home to kind of
entertain myself and find new hobbies
and things to um you know preoccupy
myself with if it was going into a
forest or spending time learning
something new and reading so many books
but yes I think especially when we got
older there were a lot of computer
programs we could do online to do lot of
our learning and that was really helpful
especially in high school because I did
go to high school part-time but I also
learned from home part-time and I did
those online and it was really fun it
got me very prepared for online college
courses well obviously a lot of you are
not parents who homeschool their
children nor are you children who
experienced an alternative education but
I thought it would be interesting to
share just because I think there's a lot
of misconceptions and a lot of
stereotypes out there that weren't true
in my personal case I feel like my
education was very focused on reading
books and going out in nature and going
to museums and really taking my
education to a lot of different places
instead of learning all of it in one
building I think traditional schooling
as well I'm sure really prepares you for
a lot of aspects to the adult world and
all that and I I see how there are so
many positives to it and positives to
alternative education for some
individuals as well one thing for me one
thing for me is that I remember when I
first started going to school with a
huge amount of my peers I realized that
I was completely out of the loop in
regards to Trends because at home I
would just follow whatever my interests
were I also had music taste that was not
modern because my father he would listen
to kind of uh rock music and just hits
from the 70s and 80s and so that was the
music I had heard and my sister was
studying classical music so the music I
listened to was either Symphonies or
rock songs from the 80s I remember
walking into school and hearing about
Taylor Swift for the first time and
um wondering if anyone knew about Billy
Joel oh my goodness it was hilarious
thinking of my 11 year old self trying
to convince people to listen to Billy
Joel instead of Taylor Swift it's it's a
it's it's hilarious and don't worry I
bought a Taylor Swift album immediately
after going to school because I realized
I needed to catch up with what the cool
kids were doing but yes I hope this
video was entertaining and different and
unique I think that I had a rather
unusual childhood I think not only
alternative schooling but paired with
moving a lot due to my father's job and
experiencing other countries in a
military setting is um is a interesting
combination so I just thought it would I
would share it for entertainment
purposes do share your academic
experiences what type of schooling did
you do and did you find it extremely
positive or negative I know I've met
friends who went to boarding school
others who went to very rigorous intense
academic programs and I think there's so
much interest and wisdom and stories to
be shared so I'm wishing you all a
wonderful week I'm sending all of you my
love I did not have a video last week
because I had a cold but I'm doing much
better now so I will see you very soon
take care goodbye
thank you
[Music]
foreign